ERIN CROTEAU

Energy Efficiency Incentive Program Implementation and Technical Support

Erin Croteau is an energy efficiency consultant with twelve years of experience in the energy efficiency industry. Her experience includes program and contractor support and training in residential energy efficiency, currently for the County of Los Angeles's Southern California Regional Energy Network (SoCalREN) Multifamily Program and previously for the SoCalREN Single Family Home Upgrade Program and the Southern California Edison/Southern California Gas Company (SCE/SoCalGas) Energy Upgrade California Home Upgrade Program which included multi-unit (2-4 unit) residential buildings. She previously performed assessments and inspections for commercial lighting in multifamily, retail, hospitality, and education (K-12 and university) sectors in Direct Install and mid-stream utility programs. She also performed energy efficiency assessments for public agencies including lighting, HVAC, plug load, and water usage. She has provided customer education, outreach, and energy efficient lighting product demonstration on behalf of utility clients.

Project Experience

SoCalREN Multifamily Program—County of Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California, 012/2018 – Present

Technical Reviewer. Erin performs technical reviews of whole-building energy efficiency upgrade projects for the SoCalREN Multifamily Program, ensuring project scope, cost, and energy savings calculations are correct, and that projects meet program requirements. She maintains direct communication with customers and engineers for project support. She also assesses new strategies and develops processes and templates for the Multifamily Program.

SoCalREN Energy Upgrade California Home Upgrade— County of Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California, 07/2017 – 12/2018

Program/Account Manager. Erin was the Program Manager and an Account Manager in the Single Family program. She provided program and project tracking and oversight, and program coordination with investor-owned utilities (regional and statewide). She also provided contractor account management including onboarding and training as well as daily communication with contractors for project and customer support.



Years of Experience

- Professional start date: 04/2008
- ICF start date: 10/2014

Education

 B.S., Environmental Science, Humboldt State University

Professional Development Training (SCE Education Center):

- Lighting Academy (12 course series including Outdoor, Commercial, and Industrial Lighting Applications)
- Implementing Energy Efficiency Projects
- Benchmarking Energy Use in Commercial Buildings (ENERGY STAR Portfolio Manager)
- Overcoming Objections to Energy Efficiency Investments
- EnergyPro Software for Beginners
- Energy Management Systems
- IHACI California Quality Installation, Maintenance, and Service (HVAC course series)
- Demand Response (Gain an Edge on Power Costs and Calculating Load Reduction)

Certifications

 Building Analyst Professional Certification, Building Performance Institute

Energy Upgrade California Home Upgrade—SCE and SoCalGas, Irvine, California, 10/2014 – 07/2017

Project Coordinator. Erin provided contractor training and support as well as project reviews, weekly client reports, data analysis, data request support, Home Performance with ENERGY STAR program reporting, contractor communications and newsletters, and worked with the Marketing Team to provide website and program document content and editing, as well as responding to public and homeowner questions submitted on the program website and the information hotline.

Customer Education, Outreach, and Inspections for Utility Clients—Organizational Support Services, Signal Hill, California, 04/2012 – 10/2014

Energy Efficiency Services Representative. While employed by Organizational Support Services, Erin provided customer education, outreach, and inspection services on behalf of utility clients SCE, SoCalGas, and SDG&E. For SCE, this included running SCE's booths at special events, answering customers questions/concerns about the utility and how to save money on their monthly utility bill, informing customers of rebates they may be eligible for (such as Energy Upgrade California and ENERGY STAR home appliance rebates), and enrolling them in utility programs they are eligible for (income-qualified, medically-qualified, etc.); as well as inspections of stores, hotels, schools, and assisted living facilities for their mid-stream lighting program to ensure compliance with program rules. For SoCalGas, this included in-store education of customers and sales staff about energy-efficient appliance rebates and assisting customers in applying for rebates. For SDG&E, this included in-store demonstrations educating customers and sales staff about energy efficient lighting technologies, how to choose the best lighting for their specific application, and assisting them in finding those lighting products in the store.

Project Analyst and Energy Services Representative—FCI Management Consultants, Inc., Long Beach, California, 04/2008 – 12/2012

Project Analyst and Energy Services Representative. While employed by FCI Management Consultants, Inc., Erin conducted public agency and commercial energy efficiency assessments including lighting, HVAC, plug load, and water usage. She analyzed energy savings based on existing equipment and utility bill history. Erin calculated project costs including materials and labor. She created reports for customers showing existing usage, recommended changes and potential energy and cost savings, and calculated payback periods for retrofit energy efficiency projects. She researched and priced new energy efficiency products. As an Energy Services representative, Erin performed energy assessments/inspections for small businesses and multifamily properties for SCE and the Los Angeles Department of Water and Power (LADWP)/SCPPA Direct Install programs. She performed field training for new hires of energy efficiency programs.

Employment History

ICF: Energy Efficiency Consultant - Indianapolis, Indiana 10/2019 - Present

Technical Reviewer - Los Angeles, California 12/2018 – 10/2019, Program Manager - Los Angeles, California 12/2017 – 12/2018, Account Manager - Los Angeles, California 07/2017 – 09/2018, Project Coordinator - Irvine, California 10/2014 – 07/2017.

Organizational Support Services: Energy Efficiency Services Representative - Signal Hill, California 04/2012 – 10/2014.

FCI Management Consultants, Inc: ESR II & Project Analyst - Long Beach, California 04/2008 – 12/2012.